

NGUYỄN VĂN BẢN

Junior Brand Manager (Open for Senior ABM)

Tan Binh Dict, HCMC

April 2nd 1997

SUMMARY 4+ years of concrete experiences in brand marketing field (FMCG) with diversely hands-on skills in both planning and leading execution. Besides, having fundamental understanding about trade & sales channel (both GT & MT) is one of strengths that I have accumulated on my career path.

> A person who drives individual long-term growth by continuously scaling up practical experiences & skills, ear to learn for progression & impressive

WORK EXPERIENCES

HYPERION Category: Imported Consumer Goods

Key Account Manager (Morden Trade Sale, 3 months) - 50 brands with over 400 SKUs

- Manage key customers of the MT channel & lead sales activities to achieve the objectives/targets with the assigned sales channel.
- Build good relationship with customers to develop and maintain the merchandising status by listing new potential SKUs, ensuring facing in stores, proposing sales policies & promotion schemes to push up sell-in/sell-out.
- Work with the trade MKT/MKT department to execute route to market plan for new SKUs, negotiate for in-store activation & displaying.
- Do monthly listing plan, promotion plan, sales monthly report to review weak/strong SKUs and propose action plans for channel, deal execution with category merchandiser (supermarket buyers).

Key Achievements: get 92% target in first month (achieved 2nd KPI bonus) & 129% target in second month (achieved highest KPI bonus).



VSK GROUP | Category: Nutritional Beverages (Bird's Nest Drink/Milk & More)

Junior Brand Manager (Jun 2022 – March 2024) – KID'S NEST PLUS+ & GENNEST (belong to YÉN SÀO THIÊN VIỆT)

- Manage entire branding activities of 02 Mom & Kids brands to achieve sales volume target and business objectives.
- Plan and lead team to deliver all brand projects related to portfolio innovations, new products launching, social communication, paid media, CRM support, sale & trade toolkits production.
- · Assist category manager in building annual marketing plan, propose monthly execution calendar for each activity and ensure firming.
- Build up communication, paid media budget plan for both AWO contents & campaign, lead team to execute rightly on time by KPI.
- Closely work with trade MKT on seasonal sales programs, route to market plan for new products, toolkits/POSM design or promotion gift planning & production.
- Ensure MKT activities to run on time by monthly/quarterly budget firming, propose next annual budget & operation plan for assigned brands.

Key Achievements: delivered innovation project with new brand identity for KID's NEST PLUS+ for in 2023; launched over 10 new products for both brand (include different flavors).



PHAM NGUYÊN CONFECTIONARY | Category: Confectionary

Assistant Brand Manager (Jun 2021 - Dec 2021) - Group brands (Pie/Sponge Cake/Biscuit)

- Assist Brand Manager in executing new products launching, sales & trade toolkits design for TÉT campaign, deliver packaging production.
- Assist Brand Manager in building up MKT strategy & 2022 AOP (Annual Operation Plan).
- Plan for thematic promotion campaign "Choco PN Cào 100% Trúng" with scheme: buy products, scratch cards and win gifts.

Key Achievements: delivered TÉT campaign, pre-launch stage for Choco PN promotion and end-to-end launched 01 new products.



YAHON ENTERPRISE Category: Homecare products

Brand Executive (Sep 2019 - May 2021) - LET-GREEN & OEM Products

- Execute brand activities focusing on Below The Line activities (display, promotion, gift with purchase, product listing)
- Plan and execute new product projects from R&D to launching stage, propose route to market with trade plan, responsible for OEM product
- · Visit market and do store checking, report monthly sales performance of brands to review by channel, product lines and propose actions for sales volume's improvement.

Key Achievements: launched 03 new products brand and get annual sales growth rate with +18.4% for LET-GREEN brand.

EDUCATION

University of Finance and Marketing (UFM)

Bachelor Degree in Marketing Management

SKILLS

Project management

Data collect & analysis

Public presentation

Oriented & logical mindset

Operational planning

Creative briefing